

Deepak Raghuwanshi

Cloud DevOps & Infrastructure Automation Engineer 9425045390 | RAGHUWANSHIDEEPAK79.DR@GMAIL.COM | in







PROFESSIONAL SKILLSET

Cloud Platforms - AWS, Azure, GCP **Automation Tools** – PowerShell, Python Continuous Integration (CI) - Jenkins Version Control Tools - GIT, GitLab IAAC - Terraform, Ansible Servers - Windows, Linux Ticket & ITIL - Service-Now

AWARDS QUARTELY AWARD

Best Performance | 2019 - 2020

EDUCATION

Bachelors Computer Applications Amity University | Gwalior 2015 - 2018

Minor degree in Animation Amity University | Gwalior 2017 - 2018

ABOUT ME

Hi, I am Deepak Raghuwanshi, currently working with Tieto.

I belong to Ashok Nagar a small & beautiful town in MP.

I would love to work with organization, where I can use my skills & knowledge for the growth of our organization.

CONTACT INFO











PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Passionate technical professional & contributor specializing in Cloud DevOps | Infrastructure Automation & integration, with a unique ability to map the needs of the business to the technology with 4.1+ Years of Experience in DevOps and Infrastructure engineering.

EXPERIENCE

Configuration Engineer | Azure Cloud DevOps Tieto | Nov 2021 - Till Date



- Design & Implement automations for manual Process on Azure, Onpremises infrastructure with PowerShell, Bash, Azure DevOps, Python
- Create & Manage Infrastructure & Configuration with Terraform Docker, PowerShell, AZDO Pipeline on the Azure Environment.
- Troubleshoot Any Failures Related to Infrastructure AZDO Pipelines, Agents & TF State, Docker, App Service, Function App, AD & IAM, Compute resources & hosted Solutions Logs, Network & NSGs ETC.
- Sync ups with the Clients & DEV Team to understand architecture for Provisioning resources with DevOps Practices & IAAC Tools.
- Create & Manages AZDO Projects, Git Repositories & Branch Polices & Restrictions, Terraform Modules.
- Setup & manages core azure pipelines & YAML def, configuring Agents for Self-hosted CICD VMs & Docker, KV, Networking etc.
- Document & Deploy Solution to higher Environments, while taking the complete handover & ownership of solutions for maintaining sol, with roll back strategies in place.
- ❖ Assist build Teams to implement DevOps Practices & familiarize with the DevOps and IAAC tools, PR Reviews & Approval, Code Quality Analysis, resolving merge conflicts & re-structuring history with Rebase, cheery pick or reverting commits.
- Implemented Automations for Crendtials, Certificate, Registration Management, Monitoring Pipeline & Applications Status & other routine manual activities.
- ❖ Knowledge Transfer to Dev & Internal Members for the tools like Terraform, GIT, PowerShell & python Automations, Network Architectures & assist team to implement DevOps ways.

PROCESS AUTOMATED

File System - Disk Usage Issues, Disk Extension, Remove Temp & Unused VM Binaries.

Compute – Automated Provisioning & De-Provisioning of VM, Create & Manage Workspace, Host Down & Ping Failure Events & Resolution, Complete Health Checks

REPORTING - Automated Reports In Excel & HTML

Active Directory - Managing Inactive Users, compliance, Access

ALERTS - Monitor a Metrics & Send the alert using SMTP Server

CERTIFICATES

AWS Certified

Cloud Practitioner | 2020

Microsoft Certified

Azure Fundamentals | 2021

HashiCorp Certified

Terraform Associate | 2021

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Expert

HINDI

Expert

FRENCH

Learning

PERSONAL DETAILS



+91 9425045390





RAGHUWANSHIDEEPAK79.DR @GMAIL.COM



Otr. No. 06, Kotwali Campus, behind new Collectorate office building, Ashok Nagar, MP-473331

EXPERIENCE

Infrastructure Process Automation | Cloud DevOps Wipro | July 2018 – Nov 2020



- Collecting and understanding requirements by syncing with client.
- ❖ Analyzing the Standard Operating Procedure shared by client.
- ❖ Designing Logic & workflow for the solution & start development.
- Presented & Explained Design Documents to client for Approval.
- Developed Solution for Server Administrative Activities like Monitoring Performance, Health Checks, Vulnerability Fixes, Certificate Management, Azure-AD & Active Directory, 0365, Exchange, Pre & Post Checks Patch, Task scheduling and background job processing etc.
- Developed & Implemented Solution for Creating & Managing Workspace, Virtual Marching on AWS, Azure & VM Ware as per business requirements.
- ❖ Developed Solutions for reporting, Processing & Consolidating data from Various sources service-now or data Repository to one master report with Custom Dashboard in Excel or HTML based reports.
- Expert with Exception & Error Handling while Maintaining readable but detailed Error Logs for Quick Debugging & troubleshooting.
- Experience in provisioning Dev & Test Environment on Azure and AWS using Terraform & Configuration with ansible.
- Experience in Source code management by performing multiple operations on Gitlab and Repository Servers. Managed projects and Individual repositories of each project created multiple repos, Edited roles and permission for users based on access protocols.
- Experience in creating pipelines on Azure DevOps & Jenkins.
- **Experience** with Automation testing with selenium web driver.
- Hands on Experience in Containerization Environments with Docker and orchestrator with Kubernetes.
- knowledge on Quality and Analysis with SonarQube & JFrog.

DECLARATION

I hereby insist that the information provided is accurate to the best of my facts and belief.